pffcu.org 2001-12-05

# PFFCU - Loans Made Faster and Easier

  | 

**_Privacy Policy_**  

Police and Fire Federal Credit Union and PFFCU Financial Services LLC. are committed to making available financial products and services that will enable you to meet your financial needs and reach your financial goals. We strive to earn your TRUST by providing quality financial products, at attractive prices, delivered with superior service, value and convenience! Part of this trust is protecting your personal information and using it in a manner consistent with your expectations. This is a high priority for everyone associated with PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services LLC. 

As a member of PFFCU, we also have a responsibility to safeguard your financial information. To ensure that you can rely upon the quality of products and services we make available, PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services, LLC. stand behind the following privacy policy: 

  * **PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services, LLC. will only collect the personal information that is necessary to conduct our business.** This means just what is necessary to provide competitive financial products and services—and no more. We may collect nonpublic information about you from the following sources: 
    * Information we receive from you on applications and other forms 
    * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others; and 
    * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency. 
  * **PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services, LLC. will protect your personal information.** PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services LLC. will maintain strong security controls to ensure that member information in our files and computers is protected. Where appropriate, we will use security coding techniques to protect against unauthorized access to personal records, ensure accuracy and integrity of communications and transactions, and protect member confidentiality. 
  * **You will always have access to your information.** As a member of PFFCU, and/or a customer of PFFCU Financial Services LLC. you will always have the opportunity to review your information and make necessary changes to ensure that our records are complete and accurate. 
  * **PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services LLC. will only share information when absolutely necessary.** We do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about our members and former members, except where permitted by law. We may disclose the following information to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf, or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements: 
    * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your name and address.
    * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, as permitted by law, or others, such as the particular types of loans or share accounts you have with us. 
We may disclose all of the information we collect, as described above to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf, or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. 
  * **PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services, LLC. adheres to strict confidentiality.** PFFCU and PFFCU Financial Services, LLC. adheres to strict confidentiality. We restrict access to non public information about you to those employees who need to know that information, for example, in order to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to guard your nonpublic personal information. 

  * **Fair Credit Reporting Act Disclosure.** In this notice, we are required to also advise you of our disclosure policy under the Fair Credit Reporting Act. The Fair Credit Reporting Act governs the sharing of information that may impact upon you for certain purposes such as credit, collections and insurance. We learn information about you from our experience with you and from information provided by others, such as through credit reports. The Fair Credit Reporting Act permits us and we do share information from our experience with you with others, including credit reporting agencies. The Fair Credit Reporting Act permits us to share information we learn from others unless you direct us otherwise. If we elect to share information about you we learn from others for a purpose under the Fair Credit Reporting Act, we will give you a separate notice of our intention to do so and the right to direct us not to share the information.

  * **E-Mail Addresses.** If you supply us with your email address, we will store that address in your member file. We may contact you by email with information about PFFCU products and services and product enhancements that may be of interest to you. You will have the opportunity to tell us you do not want to receive these product messages any time you receive one of these messages. You may also request that we remove your email address from our email list at any time by sending an email to [Member Service](https://pffcu.org/forms/email_survey.asp) and requesting that we remove your email address from our email list. Please include your name and account number in your request. 

If you have any questions regarding the Credit Union’s Privacy Statement, please do not hesitate to contact us!

**_Web Site Disclosures_**  
Anything you see, hear, read or download from this web site is made available to you in the spirit of sharing with members of the Police and Fire Federal Credit Union and potential members of PFFCU. We have worked, and are continually working hard to ensure that all the information contained in the web site is current, accurate and usable. This information should be construed only as guideline. All PFFCU information, including, but not limited to rates, yields and offers, including information contained in this web site, is subject to change, at any time, without notice. 

Before relying on, or using any information contained in the PFFCU web site that you feel may be questionable, you should contact the Credit Union at MemberService@PFFCU.org, or call our Telephone Member Service Department at 215-931-0300 or 800-288-8801, to ask for additional information.

All software or other services that we provide directly for use, or that this is created by third parties under contract with PFFCU and is provided on our site, is offered with the all terms, conditions, warranties and disclaimers listed above. Additionally, all services, products and information are provided “as is”.

All links or other connections to other Internet web sites, or mention or reference to other companies is solely for informational purposes to PFFCU members, and should not be construed as an endorsement or relationship other than what is plainly stated where such connection is made. 

**_Equal Housing Lender Notice_**

**UNDER THE FEDERAL FAIR HOUSING ACT IT IS ILLEGAL, ON THE BASIS OF RACE, COLOR, NATIONAL ORIGIN, RELIGION, SEX, HANDICAP, OR FAMILIAL STATUS (HAVING CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 18), TO :**

  * Deny a loan for the purpose of purchasing, construction, improving, repairing or maintaining a dwelling, or deny any loan secured by a dwelling; or 
  * Discriminate in fixing the amount, interest rate, duration, application procedures or other terms or conditions of such a loan, or in appraising property 

**IF YOU BELIEVE YOU HAVE BEEN DISCRIMINATED AGAINST, YOU SHOULD SEND A COMPLAINT TO:**  
Assistant Secretary for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity  
Department of Housing & Urban Development  
Washington, DC 20410 

For processing under the Federal Fair Housing Act and to

National Credit Union Administration  
Office of Examination and Insurance  
1775 Duke St., Alexandria, VA 22314-3428

For processing under NCUA regulations

**UNDER THE EQUAL CREDIT OPPORTUNITY ACT, IT IS ILLEGAL TO DISCRIMINATE IN ANY CREDIT TRANSACTION:**

  * On the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, marital status, or age, 
  * Because income is from public assistance, or 
  * Because a right was exercised under the Consumer Credit Protection Act. 

**IF YOU BELIEVE YOU HAVE BEEN DISCRIMINATED AGAINST,  
YOU SHOULD SEND A COMPLAINT TO:** National Credit Union Administration  
Office of Examination and Insurance  
775 Duke St., Alexandria, VA 22314-3428

**_Home Mortgage Disclosure Act (HMDA) Notice_**  
The HMDA data about our residential mortgage lending are available for review. The data shows the geographic distribution of loans and applications; race, gender, and income of applicants and borrowers; and information about loan approvals and denials. Inquire at any branch office regarding the locations where HMDA data may be inspected. 

**_Expedited Funds Availability Act (Regulation CC)_**

The length of delay for availability of deposits is counted in business days from the day of your deposit. Every day except Saturday, Sunday and a federal holiday is a business day. A deposit to an ATM before 3:00 p.m. is considered a deposit for that business day. Deposits after these times or on a day we are not open will be considered made on the next business day we are open.

**_SAME DAY AVAILABILITY_** \- Funds from electronic direct deposits to your account will be available on the day we receive the deposit.

**_NEXT DAY AVAILABILITY_** \- Funds from the following deposits are available on the first business day after the day of your deposit: U.S. Treasury checks that are payable to you; Wire transfers; Checks drawn on the Police and Fire Federal Credit Union.

If you make the deposit in person to one of our staff members, funds from the following deposits are also available on the first business day after the day of your deposit: Cash; State and local government checks that are payable to you, cashier’s, certified, and teller’s checks that are payable to you; Federal Reserve bank checks, Federal Home Loan Bank checks, and postal money orders, if these items are payable to you.

If you do not make your deposit to one of our employees, in person, funds from these deposits will be available on the second business day after we receive your deposit.

$100.00 of a deposit that includes both local and/or non-local checks.

**_SECOND DAY AVAILABILITY_** \- Local checks indicated by the following first four digits from the routing numbers: 0310, 0311, 0312, 0313, 0319, 2310, 2311, 2312, 2313, 2319, 2360.

**_FIFTH DAY AVAILABILITY_** \- Non-Local checks, including all checks with all other routing numbers.

**_LONGER DELAYS_** \- Longer delays may occur if we believe a check you deposit will not be paid, your account has been open less than 30 days, your total deposit for one day exceeds $5,000.00, you redeposit a check that has been returned unpaid, you have a repeatedly overdrawn account in the past six months, or a bank emergency. In such cases, you will be notified of the delay, and generally, the money will be available no later than the eleventh business day after the deposit. 

|   |    

|
